## COVER LETTER (see **bottom**)

 $FOLLOW-up \ state \ health \ dept \ | \ https://www.linkedin.com/posts/mandi-pratt-chapman-ba92976\_patientnavigation-healthequity-cancercontrol-activity-7151003727028486144-ZQ6R?utm\_source=share&utm\_medium=member\_desktop$ 

2024-12-12 - zero in: ADaM, cdisc, SDTM, TEAL?, - find better search: Indeed, Zip, etc ... DDg, google maybe better than website's search;

Too many SAS; too much digging; can not single out "R" - Navits Partners - MANY posts on Indeed/zip (mostly Indian; probably job shop) - LinkedIn - note to "Ben Jones", recruiter ... Can I start chats with a few recruiters?? - TALK TO PEOPLE; click, click, click is time sink

- Indeed (https://www.indeed.com/advanced\_search?q=R%20regression&l=) too many SAS,
- Zip

2024-09-12 - 2 resumes, SEE  $\sim$ /code/docs/jobs - 2 directories, one for ; one *clinical trials* - use quarto for actual resumes (why? I am in R world; Rstudio is very good Quarto)

2024-03-11 - Washington DC (changed my LI address - fool recruiters- experiment)

2024-01-16 - LI - finally something worked; posit's federal salesperson gave me some ideas, including openscapes 2024-01-14 - r-blogger: https://www.r-bloggers.com/2022/03/which-data-science-skills-are-important-50000-increase-in-salary-in-6-months/ - LinkedIn ... excellent ideas in youtube videos 000\_job - resume - study examples (see linked in learning by practice statistcis??

## 2024-01-11

- Work for IT staffing company on government project??
- GSA 986 repos, 9 R repos! (Is this right way to search??)

2024-01-09 - Ore job fare, 1 recruiter VERY good - job description ambiguous? ask the recruiter - Oregon: use "Behavior Based Questions", STAR, Video Interview(https://www.oregon.gov/jobs/Paginterviewing-applicants.aspx) - Oregon: STAR, interview Q: https://www.oregon.gov/jobs/Pages/support.aspx

2024-01-08 - resume & cover ltr, much better(no, not perfect) - locating R jobs, do I qualify?? - filling out job apps - NOT way to go - Ask recruiters? How do I be more attractive? 2024-01-02 - Oregon, wrote directly to 'recruiter' asking how to zero in on R needs? - Minnesota DHS is R shop (just hired someone) - Do this by state??

- Upwork, refuses to accept resume/linked ... unable to proceed.

## 2024-01-01

#### **DEAD**

- code.gov, once hot seems gone.
- fecgov, same ... but now??

# Time to find job and zero in.

2023-08-26

# Life/Job Notes, 2023-08-26

- 1. Costs: Monday will go to Patrick Olson to see about repair costs and junk it costs. When I called about oil changes, he said he had 3 week backlog and so entirely possible he's won't eeven look at car for a few days.
- 2. Costs: I have plenty of insurance, but usually with large deductibles and NO collision. Expect liability for red truck to add to cost.
- 3. Reason for *no collison*: if repair cost is more than say \$1000 it makes little sense to fix car (original cost was \$3500). I didn't think *parking* would be large *collision* damage. (*collison* sounds like, well, a collision).
- 4. Sleeping in office last few weeks (heat) but not a wise or extended strategy.
- 5. **Electric Vehicles** absolutely need to do research. My monthly driving, 100-200 miles, means that OLDER, electric vehicles, with range less than 100 miles per charge could be ideal for. I suspect most buyers, for new or used, want much higher miles per change. Need to see if prices reflect this.

#### https://www.recurrentauto.com/research

Not going to buy this one, but example of \$6000+ used EV (car + needed repairs); 50K miles https://www.autotrader.com/marketplace/buy/nissan/leaf/2012/JN1AZ0CP3CT017447? listingId=689873778 4. On bright side, this time for first time in many years began actively looking for work (resumes, contacting people). Though I have plenty of minuses, the area of softwareI know has fairly high demand. (Not as high as kidneys or kidney doctors, but still ample). There is work for a regular company (on-side) and then there is project work; which is often remote via internet or on-site. Eugene is not ideal place, though I remain very comfortable here. Important: must stay with this and NOT be distracted by cars.

Cover letter (Dec 2024) I am an R developer with a Pharmaverse project, working on various issues, documentation, coding related to ADaM, Admiral, CDISC standards. The work is entirely in R and R packages, plus github tools, to insure adherence to tidyverse style, 97% + testing coverage and the like. Some TEAL (shiny) and related R experience roughly upto metaprogramming.

# jim Rothstein

```
jimrothstein@gmail.com
(831) 824-4304 (messages)
https://www.linkedin.com/in/jimrothstein
https://github.com/jimrothstein
```

# Clinical Trials Package Developer (R)

#### Overview

R package developer. Worked with pharmaverse, including admiral, and pilot5 JSON delivery to FDA. Worked with CDISC standards, such a ADaM, SDTM, and including schema and REST api. Seek to focus on Clinical Trials R package development.

## Related Skills

- R, 4+ years
- tidyverse, httr2, data.table, shiny, quarto ...
- SQL: 2+ years, joins, dplyr
- Rstudio, emacs, neovim
- admiral, admiraldev, sdtmchecks
- github
- zsh shell
- linux

# Recent Projects & Skills

- (active) Fix issues in Pharamaverse Admiral and sdmtchecks R packages. Attend developer meetings.
- (active) Using Shiny developed preliminary dashboard for analysis of Drug Benefit Denials (public data from Center for Medicare and Medicaid (CMS)).
- (active) Used youtube API and httr and httr2 to add/modify youtube.com playlists. Used OAUTH tokens scope. Active participant developing book Web APIs with R, using openAPI framework.
- Used tools in rrapply, tidyr, vctrs, tibblify to unravel deeply nested JSONs in tree/json format to table (from REST apis)
- (active) Contribute to various Open Source projects (Github)

## **RELATED WORK HISTORY:**

2014 - present **R-Coders** Self-employed R programmer.

1996-2014 Self-employed contractor, including

- Webmaster, community expatriate website in China, 2005 2008 Setup, maintain, promote expat community-based website in Dalian, China. Selected Joomla, hosting company, hired and trained student volunteers.
- Capital IT Group, Dalian, China 2004- Mentor Chinese software engineers, light project management, pre and post sales.
- Center for Electronic Art, San Francisco, 2002 Taught Java, mySQL, jsp classes. Also supervised graduate student modeling shipping/ ordering/ inventory system.
- Teaching (1998-2012) Taught classes java, math, internet, statistics in China and California community college in US. Certified to teach math in at California community college.

Webmaster, Saratoga Systems, Campbell, CA (1996-1998) Maintain NT and IIS server. Various internet projects.

Web Database Development, Microsoft, Redmond, WA (1996) Web database applications using Asp, MS SQL; contractor.

Contract Programming Assignments: Chicago, IL (1986-1996) Designed and developed variety of business database applications (Paradox, Delphi, Access) For example

- Developed relational database model for insurance company to track debt and assets of its multi-billion dollar joint ventures/commercial properties.
- Developed order tracking system (paradox).
- Contributed to bank risk management tool (ms access)

# **Education**

BS MIT, physics

Jim Rothstein – jimrothstein@gmail.com – (831) 824-4304